(怪獸：日文中的巨型猛獸)
(機甲獵人：德文中的獵人)
When I was a kid,
小時候
whenever I'd feel small or lonely, I'd look up...
每當我感到渺小或寂寞我會
at the stars.
仰望星空
Wondered if there was life up there.
好奇宇宙中是否存在其他生命
Turns out I was looking in the wrong direction.
結果我完全看錯方向了
When alien life entered our world it was from deep beneath the pacific ocean.
當外星生物入侵，他們其實來自太平洋深處
A fissure between two tectonic plates.
兩個地殼板塊上的裂縫
A portal between dimensions.
是通往其他次元的大門
The breach.
又稱突破點
I was fifteen when the first Kaiju made land in San Francisco.
我十五歲時，第一隻怪獸在舊金山上岸
By the time tanks, jets and missiles took it down
當坦克、戰鬥機和飛彈，終於殲滅牠後
six days and 35 miles later,
已歷時六天，行經三十五英里
three cities were destroyed.
三座城市…被夷為平地
(舊金山舉市致哀)
Tens of thousands of lives were lost.
死傷上萬人
We mourned our dead,
我們哀悼罹難者
memorialized the attack,
追思攻擊事件
and moved on.
然後繼續向前
And then,
然而
only six months later,
僅僅六個月後
(怪獸排泄物汙染城市)
第二波攻勢襲擊馬尼拉
the second attack hit Manila.
The acid factor of the Kaiju blood creates a toxic phenomenon named Kaiju Blue.
怪獸血液中的酸性物質，形成一種叫做怪獸藍的毒素
And then the third one hit Cabo.
然後第三隻襲擊墨西哥海岸
And then the fourth.
緊接著是第四隻
And then we learned,
此刻我們了解到
this was not gonna stop.
這不會停止
This was just the beginning.
這只是開頭
We needed a new weapon.
我們需要新武器
The world came together,
全世界團結起來
pooling its resources and throwing aside old rivalries for the sake of the greater good.
結合資源，為了共同利益摒棄成見
(團結便能終結戰爭)
To fight monsters,
為了對抗怪獸
we created monsters of our own.
我們打造了自己的怪物
The Jaeger program was born.
獵人計劃因而誕生
There were setbacks at first.
一開始遭遇了挫折
The neural load to interface with a Jaeger proved too much for a single pilot.
單一駕駛無法負荷，與機甲獵人進行神經元介面接合
A two-pilot system was implemented.
雙駕駛系統應運而生
Left-hemisphere, right-hemisphere pilot control.
左右大腦分別由兩位駕駛控制
We started winning.
我們開始獲勝
Jaegers stopping Kaijus everywhere.
(人類反擊
群眾慶祝第二架機甲獵人勝利)
機甲獵人處處大敗怪獸
But the Jaegers were only as good as their pilots.
然而機甲獵人的表現取決於駕駛
So Jaeger pilots turned into rock stars.
因此機甲獵人駕駛變成熱門偶像
Danger turned into propaganda.
真實危機被轉為活動宣傳
Kaijus into toys.
而怪獸被視為玩具
(羅密歐藍對抗苦難)
We got really good at it.
我們開始戰無不克
Winning.
屢戰皆捷
(查獲怪獸殘肢)
Then...
然而
then it all changed.
突然間情況急轉直下
Gipsy Danger, report to Bay 08,
吉普賽危機請向八號站報到
level A-42.
層級A42
Kaiju. Code name: Knifehead. Category 3.
怪獸代號鬼頭刀，第三量級
Yo, Yancy, wake up!
楊希，快起床
Movement in the breach.
突破點有狀況
Hey, come on!
快點
We're being deployed.
我們要出征了
Great.
好極了
(阿拉斯加，2020年
怪獸戰爭第七年)
Good morning.
早安
Mornin'.
Kaiju's a category 3...
這隻是第三量級...
biggest one yet.
有史以來最大的
Code name:
代號：
Knifehead.
鬼頭刀
What time is it
現在幾點
Two
兩點
A.M.
凌晨
Yep.
沒錯
What do you say
你認為如何呢
Fifth notch on the belt
來個第五斬如何
(吉普賽危機)
Come on, Beckets. Time for the drop.
快點，貝克特兄弟，要空投了
Hey, kid.
喂，小子
Yeah
什麼
Don't get cocky.
別得意忘形了
Years before,
小時候
you wouldn't have picked my brother Yancy and I for heroes.
絕不會有人料到我哥楊希和我，日後會成為英雄
No chance.
絕無可能
Good morning, sir.
早安，長官
All right, let's suit up and kick some ass!
好了，著裝準備海扁怪獸吧
We were never star athletes.
我們從不是體育明星
Never at the head of the class.
在校成績也不好
But we could hold our own in a fight.
但打架我們從沒輸過
And it turned out we had a unique skill:
而且顯然我們有項…特殊技能
We were drift compatible.
我們具有浮動聯結的相容性
Data on helmet.
數據灌入頭盔
Data relay gel dispersing in circuitry suit.
數據傳遞乳膠灌入電路服
Good morning, Becket boys!
早安，貝克特兄弟
Tendo, what's happening, my man
天同，你好嗎兄弟
How'd that date with Alison go last night, Mr. Choi
昨晚跟愛莉森約會如何蔡先生
Oh, she loved me.
她愛死我了
Her boyfriend Not so much.
但她男友有點不爽
You're gonna get your ass kicked.
小心被人蓋布袋
A man's gotta do what a man's gotta do, brother.
這才是男性本色啊，兄弟
Engage drop, Mr. Choi.
準備空投 蔡先生
Engaging drop, sir.
空投準備中，長官
Marshal Pentecost on deck.
潘塔考斯特元帥接管控制室
Securing the conn pod.
聯結艙接合上鎖
Gettin' ready to drop.
準備空投
Conn pod door lock secure.
艙門已鎖好
Release for drop.
釋放聯結
Gipsy Danger ready for the big drop.
吉普賽危機空投準備就緒
Here we go.
來了
Yeah!
好耶
Here we go!
出發了
Coupling confirmed, sir.
合體完成，長官
Engage pilot-to-pilot protocol.
開始駕駛對駕駛程序
Engaging now.
程序開始
Pilot-to-pilot connection protocol sequence.
駕駛對駕駛聯結程序步驟
Gipsy launch,
吉普賽出發地點
bay 6.
六號站台
Gipsy Danger ready and aligned, sir.
吉普賽危機完成連線，長官
Rangers, this is Marshal Stacker Pentecost.
突擊隊員，我是潘塔考斯特元帥
Prepare for neural handshake.
準備進行神經握合
Starting in 15 seconds.
15秒後開始
Fifteen...
Thirteen...
Twelve...
Eleven...
Ready to step into my head, kid
準備進入我大腦了嗎小子
Please, after you.
沒關係，你先請
Age before beauty, old man.
我要敬老尊賢，老頭
Five...
Four...
Neural handshake,
神經握合
initiated
啟動
The drift.
浮動聯結
Jaeger tech.
機甲獵人科技
Based on DARPA jet fighter neural systems.
來自國防先進研究局的戰鬥機神經元系統
Two pilots, mind-melding through memories with the body of a giant machine.
兩名駕駛，透過回憶精神結合以控制巨型機械人的身體
The deeper the bond...
結合越深
the better you fight.
戰鬥力越強
Neural handshake strong and holding.
神經握合，堅強且穩固
Right hemisphere is calibrating.
右大腦半球進行校準
Left hemisphere calibrating.
左大腦半球進行校準
Proofed and transmitting.
聯結交流確認
Gentlemen, your orders are to hold the Miracle Mile off Anchorage. Copy
二位，你們的任務是防衛安克拉治黃金海岸線
Copy that, sir.
收到，長官
Sir, there's still a civilian vessel in the Gulf...
長官，海灣裡還有平民船隻…
Gentlemen, you're protecting a city of 2 million people.
你們要保衛城裡兩百萬居民
You will not risk those lives for a boat that holds 10. Am I clear
不要為船上少數人冒險
Yes, sir.
-明白嗎
-明白了，長官
Man, that's cold.
老天，真無情
You know what I'm thinking.
你知道我在想什麼
I'm in your brain.
我在你腦裡
I know.
當然知道
Then let's go fishing.
咱們去捕魚吧
Here we go!
開始了
Come on, bro! Put some muscle to it!
兄弟，使勁點
Worry about yourself, kiddo!
管好你自己吧，小子
There are things you can't fight, acts of God.
人類很難與天災人禍抗衡
You see a hurricane coming,
當風暴來襲時
you have to get out of the way.
通常躲為上策
But when you're in a Jaeger,
但當你置身機甲獵人中
suddenly,
突然間
you can fight the hurricane.
你能夠對抗風暴
You can win.
而且你能獲勝
(阿拉斯加海岸線十英里處)
Get 'em tied down,
把裝備綁好
and go down below!
下船艙躲避
Now!
現在
How far to the mainland
離岸邊有多遠
7 Miles off Anchorage, sir.
距離安克拉治七英里，船長
But we won't even make it past the shallows!
但我們連淺灘區都到不了
No, we won't!
沒錯
What about that island 3 Miles east
去這三英里外的島如何
No! No! It's 2 Miles, sir.
不，是兩英里，船長
O... one mile, sir!
一英里，船長
It's getting closer.
越來越靠近了
How the hell can it be getting closer
陸地…怎麼會移動
Kaiju.
怪獸
Harder starboard!
再往右轉
I'm doing it as fast as I can!
立刻掉頭
Now!
現在
Oh, God!
天啊
What the hell
怎麼回事
Hang on!
抓好了
Ship secure.
船隻獲救
Adjust the torque!
調整扭力
I'm on it.
我來
Torque locked.
扭力鎖定
Get him. Come on. Shoot him.
快點，射他
I'm on it! I'm on it!
-射他
-我來搞定
Discharge reading, sir.
長官，偵測顯示
Plasma Cannon in the shallow shelves 7 Miles off the coastal line.
在海岸線七英里淺灘處有等離子炮發射
Gipsy, what the hell is going on
吉普賽，發生什麼事了
Job's done, sir.
任務完成了，長官
Lit it up twice.
駁火兩次
Bagged our fifth kill.
第五斬到手
You disobeyed a direct order!
你們違反我的命令
Respectfully, sir,
無意冒犯，長官
we intercepted a Kaiju and saved everyone on that boat.
我們攔截怪獸，也救了船上的人
Get back to your post, now!
立刻返回基地
Yes, sir.
遵命，長官
Kaiju signature rising!
怪獸讀數大增
That thing's still alive, sir.
那東西還活著，長官
Gipsy!
吉普賽
We're still getting a signature!
我們持續接收到讀數
That Kaiju is still alive!
那隻怪獸還活著
Grab the boat and get out of there.
帶著船隻離開那裡
Do you copy
收到了嗎
Grab the boat and get out of there now!
立刻帶著船隻離開那裡
Take it, Raleigh!
扁他，萊利
I got this!
看我的
Loccent, we're hit!
任務控制室，我們受傷了
Left arm's gone cold, sir.
左臂斷線了，長官
The hull!
機艙
It went through the hull!
他劃破機艙了
Raleigh, listen to me!
萊利，聽我說
You need...
你得…
No!
不
Loading.
載入
Second discharge fried all the comms, sir.
第二次發射讓通訊短路
I'm not getting any signals.
我收不到任何訊號
No signatures, sir.
沒有讀數，長官
What do we do now, sir
現在該怎麼辦，長官
Now, I want you to keep your eye on that gauge there.
我要你緊盯著儀表
Now, you know what I'd like to find
知道我想找什麼嗎
I'd like to find a whole ship.
我想找一整艘船
That's what I'd like to find.
那是我想找到的
Wait, wait!
等等，等等，等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Wait! Right there, right there!
在那裡，在那裡，快挖
Hey, what is it
那是什麼
It's just an old toy.
只是個老玩具
We never find anything good.
我們從沒挖到過寶
Listen.
你聽
Oh, my God.
我的老天
Stay here!
待在那裡
Mister
先生
Can I help
你還好嗎
Yancy.
楊希
Run!
快跑
Get help, fast!
快去找人來幫忙
It's gonna be all right.
不會有事的
片名：環太平洋
The Kaiju are learning our defenses.
怪獸研究我們的防禦系統
They're adapting.
他們不斷調整
Evolving.
演化
And we're losing Jaegers faster than we can build them.
機甲獵人生產的速度遠遠趕不上失去的速度
Lima.
利馬
Seattle.
西雅圖
Vladivostok.
海參崴
Category 4 Kaijus are now coming through the breach.
第四量級怪獸開始從突破點竄出
I think even you can see, Marshal,
就連你都可看出，元帥
this is no longer a sound strategy.
這戰略已不管用
The frequency of the attacks has increased.
攻擊頻率增加
(五年後，阿拉斯加撤防日)
The Jaegers are not the most viable line of defense anymore.
機甲獵人不再是最好的防禦措施
I am aware.
我知道
Those are my rangers that die every time a Jaeger falls,
每次機甲獵人被擊毀，我的突擊隊員就殉職
which is why...
因此我要求
I'm asking you for one...
給我們最後一次機會
Excuse me, Marshal.
很抱歉，元帥
last chance.
最後一次
one final assault with everything we've got.
結集所有火力攻擊
The Jaeger program is dead, Marshal.
機甲獵人計劃已經玩完了，元帥
On the other hand,
反觀之
the coastal wall program is a promising option.
沿海圍牆計劃，則大有可為
The world appreciates all that you and your men have done,
舉世都感謝你和弟兄們的貢獻
but it's over.
但已經結束了
We will authorize you to take all remaining Jaegers to the last battle station:
我們批准你將剩餘機甲獵人運往最後作戰基地：
Hong Kong.
香港
We're prepared to fund you for the next eight months
未來八個月的築牆過程中
while the coastal wall is completed.
我們會繼續提供資金
After that,
之後
you will receive no further support.
我們就會切斷所有援助
You have your answer, Marshal.
這就是我們的決定，元帥
So that's it
就這樣
It's over
都結束了
Suits and ties,
西裝筆挺
flashy smiles.
官腔官調
That's all they are, Stacker.
他們就是這種貨色，史塔克
We don't need 'em.
我們不需要他們
(生命牆
阿拉斯加州夕卡市)
(捍衛您的未來
阿拉斯加至加州防怪獸牆)
(太平洋周邊計劃工程管理部)
(三百英里完工日：遙遙無期)
(工作換取口糧)
(危險補助
牆頂300)
Ration cards, guys!
來吧，這裡有口糧卷，來吧
Come on, come on!
來吧
Let's go!
Now, I got good news and I got bad news, fellas.
我有好消息和壞消息，各位
Which one you wanna hear first
想先聽哪個
Bad news!
壞消息
Bad news
壞消息是
Three guys died yesterday...
三人昨天
working the top of the wall.
在牆頂工作時掛了
What's the good news
那好消息呢
The good news is,
好消息是
I got three new job openings.
我現在有三個職缺
Top of the wall.
在牆頂工作
Okay, who wants to work Who wants to eat
誰想要工作誰想要糊口
Come on!
來吧
I am here in Sydney,
記者人在雪梨
where earlier today,
今天稍早
yet another Kaiju attack took place.
此處又發生怪獸攻擊事件
The Kaiju,
這隻怪獸
an enormous category 4,
是超大的第四量級
broke through the coastal wall in less than an hour.
不到一小時就突破沿岸圍牆
The wall of life had been deemed unbreachable by its builders.
建商總宣稱生命牆堅不可摧
Why the hell are we even buildin' this thing
我們幹嘛花時間蓋這鬼東西
The creature entered the city through Sydney Cove.
那怪獸通過悉尼灣進入城市
That... that thing
那...怪獸
- went through the wall like it was nothing. - Ironically...
- 三兩下就把牆毀了
- 諷刺的是…
it was the recently decommissioned Jaeger,
最近除役的機甲獵人
Striker Eureka,
衝鋒發現號
piloted by Herc and Chuck Hansen,
由赫克和查克韓森所駕駛
that finally took the beast down.
最後殲滅了巨獸
Look, they decommissioned the Jaeger Program because of mediocre pilots.
官方終止獵人計劃是因為有些駕駛太遜
It's that simple.
就這麼簡單
That's Striker Eureka's tenth kill to date.
這是衝鋒發現號的第十斬
It's a new record.
創下新紀錄
And you're still going to Hong Kong,
在這種危急關頭
even at a time like this
你們還是要移防香港嗎
Well, orders are orders. What else am I supposed to do
軍令如山，我們能怎麼辦
Come on, mate.
走吧，伙計
Chuck Hansen, one of the pilots of Striker Eureka,
那是衝鋒發現號的駕駛之一，查克韓森
the Jaeger that took down the Kaiju.
他們的機甲獵人擊殺了怪獸
Mr. Becket.
貝克特先生
Marshal.
元帥
Looking sharp.
你看起來真有型
Long time.
好久不見
Five years, four months.
五年四個月
Can I have a word
能跟你聊聊嗎
Step into my office, Marshal.
到我辦公室吧，元帥
Took me a while to find you.
花了好大功夫才找到你
Anchorage,
安克拉治
Sheldon point, nome...
謝爾登角、 諾姆
Yeah, a man in my position travels with the wall,
工人得追著牆跑
chasing shifts to make a livin'.
混口飯吃
What do you want
你想要幹嘛
I've spent the last six months activating everything I can get my hands on.
過去半年我努力搜集修復所有可用資源
There's an old Jaeger,
有台老機甲獵人
a Mark 3.
第三代的
You may know it.
你或許熟悉
It needs a pilot.
它需要駕駛
I'm guessing I wasn't your first choice.
我應該不是你的第一人選
You are my first choice.
你當然是我的首要人選
All the other mark 3 pilots are dead.
其他第三代駕駛都死光了
Look...
你聽我說
I can't have anyone else in my head again.
我不能再跟別人搞精神結合了
I'm done.
我玩完了
I was still connected to my brother when he died.
我哥死時我們神經還相連
I can't go through that again, man, I'm sorry.
我無法再承受一次這種事，抱歉
Haven't you heard, Mr. Becket
你還沒聽說嗎，貝克特先生
The world is coming to an end.
世界就要毀滅了
So where would you rather die!
你寧願死在哪裡
Here,
這裡
or in a Jaeger!
還是機甲獵人中
香港灣
十八點整
(碎頂訓練營)
(機甲獵人基地)
Mr. Becket,
貝克特先生
this is Mako Mori.
這位是森真子
One of our brightest.
我們最傑出的員工之一
Also in charge of the Mark 3 restoration program.
她負責主導第三代的修復計劃
She personally handpicked your copilot candidates.
她親自挑選你的副駕駛候選人
他跟我想像中不太一樣
Hey.
不好意思
有話可直說
當然，真抱歉，貝克特先生
我聽說很多有關你的事
At ease.
稍息
We will tour the facility first
先參觀基地
and then Miss Mori will show you to your Jaeger, Mr. Becket.
然後森小姐會帶你去看你的機甲獵人，貝克特先生
- Wait for us, please!，- Hold the door, please!
-等等
-別關門 -拜托
-謝謝，謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝
Stay back!
退後點
Kaiju specimens are extremely rare,
怪獸樣本取得不易
so look but don't touch, please.
所以請勿觸碰
Mr. Becket, this is our research team.
貝克特先生，這是我們的研究小組
Dr. Gottlieb
葛裡布博士
and Dr. Geiszler.
和蓋斯勒博士
Oh, no, call me Newt.
不，請叫我牛頓
Only my mother calls me Doctor.
只有我媽才叫我博士
Hermann,
賀曼
these are human beings. Why don't you say hello
這些是人類，快打招呼
I have asked you not to refer to me by my first name around others.
我說過別在旁人面前直呼我名字
I am a doctor with over 10 years decorated experience...
我是個十餘年來獲獎
10 years of experience, man. I'm very sorry.
無數的博士
失敬了
Oh, please.
拜託
Who is that, Yamarashi
那隻是山嵐嗎
Oh, this little kaiju
你是說這隻怪獸
Yeah, you got a good eye.
對，好眼力
My brother and I took him down in 2017.
我和我哥在2017年殲滅了他
You know he was one of the biggest category 3s ever
知道他是史上最大的第三量級
He was 2,500 tons of awesome.
2500公噸，雄偉壯觀
Or awful.
或是醜惡
You know, whatever you wanna call it.
隨你怎麼看
Please excuse him.
別理他
He's a kaiju groupie. He loves...
他是怪獸迷，他愛死他們
Shut up, Hermann, I don't love them, okay
閉嘴，賀曼，我不愛他們
I study them.
我只是研究他們
And unlike most people,
跟別人不同
I wanna see one alive and up close one day.
我希望有天能近距離看到隻活的
Trust me,
相信我
you don't want to.
你不會想的
So that's your research division
那就是你的研究部門
Things have changed.
情況改變了
We're not an army anymore, Mr. Becket.
我們不再隸屬軍方，貝克特先生
We're the resistance.
我們是反抗軍
Welcome to the Shatterdome.
歡迎來到碎頂訓練營
The war clock.
那是戰鬥鍾
We reset it after every Kaiju attack.
在每次怪獸攻擊後重新計時
Keeps everyone focused.
好提醒大家專心
The frequency of attacks is accelerating.
攻擊的頻率加快了
How long till the next reset
下次歸零會是何時
A week, if we're lucky.
一星期，如果走運的話
My experts believe there'll be a kaiju attack even before that.
我的專家認為在那之前怪獸就會再攻擊
This complex used to lodge 30 Jaegers in five bays just like this one.
過去曾停放三十架和這一樣的機甲獵人
Now we only have four Jaegers left.
現在只剩下四架機甲獵人
I didn't know it was this bad.
情況這麼糟呀
It is that bad.
就是這麼糟
Crimson Typhoon, China.
中國的暴風赤紅
One of the greatest.
最棒的機甲獵人之一
Assembled in Changzhou.
在常州組裝
Full titanium core, no alloys.
核心由鈦金屬鑄造，不含任何合金
Fifty diesel engines per muscle strand.
每條肌肉由五十個柴油引擎驅動
Deadly, precise fighter.
非常精確致命的
She's piloted by the Wei Tang brothers. Triplets.
由三胞胎偉唐兄弟所駕駛
Local lads.
當地人
They've successfully defended Hong Kong port seven times.
他們成功捍衛香港港口七次
They use the thundercloud formation.
使用的是雷雲陣式
Oh, yeah.
對
Triple-arm technique.
那個三臂齊出的技巧
Very effective.
非常有效
That tank, last of the T-90s.
那個老傢伙，是最後的T90
Cherno Alpha.
車諾艾爾發
First generation mark 1.
第一批生產的第一代
The heaviest and oldest Jaeger in the service.
服役中最重最舊的機甲獵人
But make no mistake, Mr. Becket,
但可別搞錯
it's a brutal war machine.
那是最驍勇的戰爭機器
And those two,
那兩位
Sasha and Aleksis Kaidanovksy.
是莎夏和艾利克斯凱德諾夫斯基
Yeah, I've heard of 'em.
對，久仰大名
Perimeter patrol, Siberian wall.
西伯利亞圍牆的邊境守衛
On they watch it stayed unbreached for six years.
在他們的看守下六年從未被攻破過
Six years.
六年
Herc!
赫克
Chuck!
查克
Gentlemen, welcome to Hong Kong!
歡迎來到香港，二位
Wait here.
你在這裡等
Max! Come here!
麥克斯，過來
Remember me
記得我嗎
Don't drool all over Miss Mori.
口水別滴到森小姐身上
Sees a pretty girl and he gets all wound up.
他一看到漂亮小姐就興奮
Raleigh, this is Hercules Hansen,
萊利，這位是赫丘裡斯韓森
an old friend from the mark 1 glory days.
第一代輝煌時期的老戰友
I know you, mate. We rode together before.
我認識你，我們曾一起出勤
We did, sir.
是的，長官
Six years ago. My brother and I.
六年前，和我哥哥一起
It was a three Jaeger team drop.
三架機甲獵人的團體行動
That's right. Manila.
沒錯，在馬尼拉
Sorry about your brother.
令兄的事很遺憾
Thank you, sir.
謝謝你，長官
Herc and his son Chuck'll be runnin' point usin' striker Eureka.
赫克和他的兒子查克，會駕駛衝鋒發現號主導我們行動
Fastest Jaeger in the world.
世上最快的機甲獵人
First and last of the mark 5s.
第一架也是最後一架第五代
Australia decommissioned it a day before the Sydney attack.
澳洲政府在雪梨被攻擊的前一天，將它除役
Yeah, it was lucky we were still around.
幸好我們還沒離開
Yep.
對
Now it's runnin' point for us.
現在它是我們的主力戰將
Wait, running point on what
等等，什麼主力戰將
You haven't told me what I'm doing here yet.
你還沒告訴我來要幹嘛
We're going for the breach, Mr. Becket.
我們要攻擊突破點
We're gonna strap a 2,400 pound thermonuclear warhead to striker's back.
我們要在衝鋒號背上，綁上2400磅的熱核子彈頭
Detonate an equivalent of 1.2 million tons of TNT,
爆炸威力等同120萬噸的黃色炸藥
and you...
你和
and two other Jaegers'll be runnin' defense for them.
其他兩架機甲獵人要提供防衛
Thought we were the resistance.
我以為我們是反抗軍
Where'd you get something that big
你哪弄來麼強的玩意兒
See the Russians back there
看到後面的俄國人嗎
They can get us anything.
他們什麼都弄得到
Herc, shall we
赫克，走吧
Good to have you back.
很高興你歸隊
Thank you, sir.
謝謝你，長官
I'll show you to your Jaeger now.
我帶你去看你的機甲獵人
Miss Mori,
森小姐
will you give me a minute
給我一分鍾好嗎
Marshal!
元帥
Sir, we've hit the breach before.
長官，我們攻擊過突破點
It doesn't work. Nothing goes through.
沒用的，沒有東西能穿透它
What's changed
現在有何不同
I've got a plan. I need you ready.
我自有計劃，我需要你準備好
That's all.
就這麼簡單
Let's go, Herc!
走吧，赫克
Max, come here!
麥克斯，過來
Crew 17, please report to the fifth floor.
17組組員請到五樓報到
Zero minus two.
零減二
XY minus two.
XＹ減2
R-e-q.
REQ
In the beginning, the kaiju attacks were spaced by 24 weeks.
一開始，怪獸攻擊間隔24周
Then twelve, then six,
後來變成12周，然後6周
then every two weeks.
之後間隔2周
The last one in Sydney was a week.
上次在雪梨是間隔1周
In four days,
四天內
we could be seeing a kaiju every eight hours
我們可能每八小時
until they are coming every four minutes.
就被襲擊
Marshal, we should witness a double event within seven days.
元帥，七天內我們可能遭遇兩次怪獸攻擊
Mr. Gottlieb,
葛裡布先生
I'm to drop a 2,400 pound thermonuclear bomb.
我準備投擲2400磅的熱核子彈頭
I need more than a prediction.
我需要更多證據而不是假設而已
Well, uh,
那…
that's a problem, then
那可是個大問題
because see, he actually can't give you anything more than a prediction.
因為他只能提供假設
No kaiju entrails over my side of the room.
我這邊不歡迎怪獸內臟
You know the rules.
你知道規矩
Every bloody day.
每天都這樣
- It's incessant.
- Gents!
-煩死了
-兩位
On point.
請說重點
Numbers do not lie.
數目不會說謊
Politics and poetry, promises, these are lies.
政治、詩詞和山盟海誓那些是謊言
Numbers are as close as we get to the handwriting of God.
數字是最接近事實的東西
What
什麼
Would you give me a moment
別打斷我
There will be a double event
絕對會出現雙重攻擊事件
and then, shortly thereafter, three. And then four.
然後緊接著是三隻、四隻
And then we're dead.
然後我們死定了
I get it.
我懂了
Alas.
很不幸
This is where the good news comes.
然而，這也帶來好消息
Here...
這是...
is our universe,
我們的宇宙
and here is theirs.
而這是他們的
And this is what we call "The throat", the passage between the breach and us.
突破點的通道我們稱為頸部
We know that it's atomic in nature.
是由原子組成的
I predict that the increased traffic
我預測交通流量的增加
will force the breach to stabilize
會使突破點穩固
and remain open long enough
並保持暢通
to get the device through...
能夠投擲武器
and collapse its structure.
並癱瘓它的結構
Yeah, and that's where I gotta chime in
講到這裡我就得插嘴
because...
因為...
really, I wouldn't wanna go in there with that limited amount of information.
我可不要依賴假設，貿然行動
- Newton, don't embarrass yourself.- That's what I was tryin' to say.
-牛頓，別自取其辱
-這就是我試著要說的
Just hear me out for a second.
就聽我說一下
Give me a second, please.
就聽我說一下，拜託
Why do we judge the kaiju on a category system
我們為何用量級歸類怪獸
It's because each one is completely different from the next, right
是因為每隻都完全不同，對吧
You see what I'm saying
知道我在說啥嗎
One looks like a shark,
有的像鯊
- and one looks like a fish...- Dr. Geiszler.
-有的像魚
-蓋斯勒博士
Just get to the point.
請講重點
Yes.
好
The point is I don't think they're all completely different after all.
重點是我覺得他們沒那麼不同
These are some samples I collected, all right
這些是我收集的樣本
Now, this one here was harvested in Sydney.
這隻是在雪梨採集的
And this was harvested in Manila.
這隻則是在馬尼拉
6 years ago.
六年前
They have the same exact DNA.
他們的DNA完全相同
They're clones.
他們是複製品
And this is the point where he goes completely crazy.
講到這個他就完全失心瘋
There's so much more to the kaiju than we understand.
關於怪獸還有很多事我們不瞭解
And we've really only scratched the surface.
我們目前只觸及皮毛
This is a piece of a kaiju's brain.
這是怪獸的大腦
Now, unfortunately, it's damaged.
很不幸受損了
It's a little bit weak.
所以功能疲弱
But it's still alive.
但它仍活著
Now, I think I can tap into it
我想我能探索它
using the same technology that allows the two Jaeger pilots to share a neural bridge.
使用機甲獵人駕駛分享神經橋的同樣科技
Now, think about that.
你們想想看
I could tell you exactly how to get through the breach yourselves.
我能告訴你們如何進入突破點
You're suggesting that we initiate a drift with a Kaiju
你建議我們跟怪獸建立浮動聯結
No, no. No, no.
不，不，不，不
Not like a whole Kaiju,
是整隻怪獸
you know, ust a tiny piece of its brain.
只一小部分的大腦
The neural surge would be too much for the human brain.
那種神經衝擊，不是人類大腦能承受的
I agree.
我同意
I don't agree.
我不同意
Gottlieb,
葛裡布
I'd like your data on my desk A.S.A.P.
快把你的研究數據交給我
Sir.
長官
No, but his is so...
不，但他的研究…
Thank you, Newt.
謝謝你，牛頓
Guys, now, this is the most amazing thing...
兩位，這是最驚人的發現…
Newton, I know that you're desperate to be right
牛頓，我知道你渴望自己是對的
so you've not wasted your life being a kaiju groupie,
這樣才沒枉費一生沉迷於怪獸
but it's not going to work.
很可惜你不會成功
It is going to work, Hermann.
這肯定會成功，賀曼
And I'll tell you something else.
我還要告訴你
Fortune favors the brave, dude.
幸運之神眷顧勇士，兄弟
You heard them.
你聽到了
They won't give you the equipment, and even if they did,
他們不會給你設備，就算他們點頭
you'd kill yourself.
你也會害死自己
Or, I'd be a rock star.
或名垂千古
There she is.
她在那裡
Oh, my God.
我的老天
Look at her.
看看她
Gipsy danger.
吉普賽危機
God,
老天
it's so beautiful.
真美
She looks like new.
看起來跟新的一樣
Better than new.
比新的更好
She has a double-core nuclear reactor.
她現在有雙核子反應爐
She's one of a kind now.
她現在是獨一無二的了
She always was.
她一直都是
How do you like your ride, Becket boy
喜歡你的坐騎嗎貝克特小子
Solid iron hull, no alloys.
純鐵機艙，不參雜合金
Forty engine blocks per muscle strands.
每條肌肉由四十個引擎傳動
Hyper-torque driver for every limb and a new fluid synapse system.
四肢配備超扭力傳動器，和全新的液體神經原系統
Come here.
過來
Tendo.
天同
It's good to see you, buddy.
真高興見到你，兄弟
It's good to see you too, brother.
我也很高興見到你，兄弟
It's just like old times.
就像以前那樣
So what's your story
你為何跑來這裡
Restoring old Jaegers,
修復舊機甲獵人
showing has-beens like me around.
帶過氣駕駛參觀
That can't be it.
不可能是為了這個
You a pilot
你是駕駛嗎
No.
不
No yet.
還不是
But I wanna be one, more than anything.
但我非常希望能成為駕駛
What's your simulator score
你的模擬器成績如何
51 drops,
51次出擊
51 kills.
51次擊殺
Wow, that's amazing.
那很棒啊
But you're not one of the candidates tomorrow
但你不是明天的候選駕駛之一
I am not.
我不是
The marshal has his reasons.
元帥自有理由
Yeah, he always does, doesn't he
他大道理一堆
But with 51 kills, I can't imagine what they could be.
但我想不出，有什麼比得過51次擊殺
I hope you approve of my choices.
希望你喜歡我替你準備的人選
I've studied your fighting techniques and strategy.
我研究你的戰鬥技巧和戰略
Even...
包括...
Alaska.
阿拉斯加那次
And what do you think
你覺得如何
I think...
我覺得...
you're unpredictable.
你不按牌理出牌
You have a habit of deviating from standard combat techniques.
你喜歡偏離標準戰鬥技巧
You take risks and injure yourself and your crew.
你選擇冒險導致自己和組員受傷
I don't think you're the right man for this mission.
我不覺得你是這任務的正確人選
Wow.
哇
Thank you for your honesty.
感謝你的誠實
You might be right.
或許你是對的
But one day, when you're a pilot,
但有一天當你成為駕駛後
you're gonna see that in combat
你會發現在戰鬥中
you make decisions.
你得做出抉擇
And you have to live with the consequences.
還得承擔那些後果活下去
That's what I'm trying to do.
我正在努力這麼做
The candidates are ready.
候選人準備好了
We will commence the trials immediately, sir.
考試即刻開始，長官
Good.
很好
But there is one thing.
但還有一件事
- We...- Mako,
-我... -真子
we have talked about this.
這件事情我們談過了
We will not be talking about it again.
不要再討論一次
You promised me.
你答應過我
(該由我和他一起駕駛吉普賽危機)
Mako.
真子
Vengeance is like an open wound.
復仇的念頭就像在傷口上灑鹽
You cannot take that level of emotion into the drift.
不能懷抱這種情緒進行浮動聯結
For my family, I need...
-為了我家人
-以後有空再說
Raleigh.
萊利
Come sit with us.
跟我們一起坐
Oh, I'm okay, thank you.
沒關係，謝謝
Ah, come on, there's plenty of room at our table.
來嘛，這裡還有很多空位
I haven't seen bread in a while.
好久沒看過麵包了
Hong Kong.
香港
Beauty of an open port,
開放港口美妙之處
no rationing.
不用配給糧食
We've got potatoes, peas, sweet beans, decent meat loaf.
這裡有馬鈴薯、青豆、甜豆、不錯的肉餅
Pass the potatoes.
把馬鈴薯給我
Raleigh, this is my son, Chuck.
萊利，這是我兒子查克
He's my copilot now.
他是我的副駕駛
He's more my copilot,
他倒像是我的副手
right, dad
她是我的副駕駛
So you're the guy, eh
對吧，老爹
You're the guy who's gonna run defense for me in that old rust bucket of yours
所以你就是那傢伙你要駕駛那架生銹的破水桶掩護我
That's the plan.
計劃是如此
Good.
很好
So,
真子
when was the last time you jockeyed, Ray
你上次駕駛是何時，阿萊
About five years ago.
大約五年前
What have you been doin' for five years
那你這五年都在做什麼
Something pretty important, I reckon.
我猜是了不起的大事
I was in construction.
我在工地打工
Oh, wow,
天啊
that's great.
真棒
That's really useful. Uh, you know.
我是說，可真實用
we get into a fight, you can build our way out of it, eh, Ray
開打時可挖條地道讓我們逃生，阿萊
It's Raleigh.
我叫萊利
Whatever.
隨便啦
Look,
聽著
you're Pentecost's bright idea.
你是潘塔考斯特找來的
My old man, he seems to like you,
我老爹好像也挺喜歡你
but it's guys like you who brought down the Jaeger program.
但獵人計劃就是被你這種人搞垮
To me,
對我而言
you're dead weight.
你只是累贅
You slow me down,
你敢擋路
I'm gonna drop you like a sack of Kaiju shit.
我會把你當怪獸一起甩掉
I'll see you around, Raleigh.
回頭見，萊利
Come, Max.
走了，麥克斯
You can blame me for that one.
這都該怪我
I've raised him on my own.
我獨自帶大他
He's a smart kid, but...
他很聰明，但...
I never knew whether to give him a hug or a kick in the ass.
我不知道該寵他還是海扁他一頓
With respect, sir...
恕我直言，長官
I'm pretty sure which one he needs.
答案應該很明顯
(候選人試驗，六點整)
4 points to zero.
四比零
4 points to 1.
四比一
4 points to 2.
四比二
Okay, what
怎麼
You don't like 'em
你不中意他們
I thought you selected them personally.
這可是你親手選的人
Excuse me
什麼意思
Every time a match ends
每次對打結束
you make this little...
你都擺出一副表情
gesture,
什麼意思
like you're critical of their performance.
好像很不滿他們的表現
It's not their performance,
不是他們的
it's yours.
是你的
Your gambit.
別盡耍小花招
You could have taken all of them two moves earlier.
你明明兩招前就可解決他們
You think so
你這麼認為
I know so.
我知道是如此
Can we change this up
不如來點新鮮的
How 'bout we give her a shot
何不給她個機會試試
Yeah!
對
No.
不
We stick to the cadet list we have, ranger.
我們從名單中挑選，突擊隊員
Only candidates with drift compatibility...
只考慮有浮動聯結相容性的…
Which I have, Marshal.
我也有，元帥
Mako, this is not only about a neural connection.
真子，這不只神經聯結
It's also about a physical compatibility.
還要考慮體能的相容性
What's the matter, marshal
怎麼了，元帥
Don't think your brightest can cut it in the ring with me
怕你最傑出的人才打不過我
Go.
上吧
Four strikes marks a win.
四次觸擊就算獲勝
Remember, it's about compatibility.
記住，比賽重點是相容性
It's a dialogue, not a fight.
這是一場對話，不是打鬥
But I'm not gonna dial down my moves.
但我不會手下留情
Okay.
好啊
Then neither will I.
那我也不會
1-0.
一比零
1-1.
一比一
2-1.
二比一
Concentrate.
專心點
2-2.
二比二
Better watch it.
最好小心點
3-2.
三比二
森小姐，控制自己
Enough.
夠了
I've seen what I need to see.
我該看的都看到了
Me too.
我也是
She's my copilot.
她是我的副駕駛
That's not going to work.
那樣行不通
Why not
為什麼
Because I said so, Mr. Becket.
因為我說了算，貝克特先生
I made my decision.
我已作好決定
Report to the shatterdome in two hours
兩小時後去碎頂訓練營報到
and find out who your copilot will be.
到時會公布副駕駛人選
Mako.
真子
What was all that about
那是怎麼回事
I mean, I'm not crazy.
我是說，不是我亂想
You felt it, right
你也有感覺對嗎
We are drift compatible.
我們有浮動聯結相容性
Thank you for standing up for me.
謝謝你替我出頭
But...
但...
there is nothing to talk about.
沒什麼好說的了
That's my room.
那是我房間
Excuse me.
抱歉
I mean, come on. I thought you wanted to be a pilot.
別這樣，你不是想當駕駛嗎
Mako, this is worth fighting for.
真子，你該為理想奮戰
We don't have to just obey him.
我們不必總是唯命是從
It's not obedience, Mr. Becket.
這跟服從無關，貝克特先生
It's respect.
這叫尊重
Would you at least tell me what his problem is
拜託告訴我，他為何反對
In the wake of the Sydney incident,
雪梨攻擊事件
which showed the ineffective nature of the Wall of Life program,
凸顯生命牆計劃的不堪一擊
many are questioning the government's motives
是的，你說過，所以你看到什麼
and wondering why the jaeger program has been discontinued.
民眾開始質疑政府動機，議論為何獵人計劃遭到腰斬
Riots have erupted along the coastlines of several pan pacific cities.
數個泛太平洋海岸城市發生暴動
We have now relocated millions of civilians and supplies...
我們已將數百萬居民和物資撤離
300 Miles inland to the safe zones.
安置到內陸三百英里處的安全區域
Safe zones For the rich and powerful
你們只管有錢有勢的人
What about the rest of us
我們怎麼辦
Yeah, answer the question.
對，快回答問題
I believe the Wall of Life
我相信此時生命牆
is still our best option at this time.
仍是最好選擇
And that's all I'm gonna say on the matter.
這是我對此事的意見
Than... thank you.
....謝謝
Kaiju/human drift experiment, take one.
怪獸人類浮動聯結實驗，第一次
The, uh...
呃...
the brain segment is the frontal lobe.
使用的是怪獸大腦額葉部分
Um...
嗯...
chances are...
很可能
the segment's far too damaged to drift with.
受損過度無法聯結
Unscientific aside:
順便插播一下
Hermann,
賀曼
if you're listening to this,
如果你聽到這個
well, I'm either alive and I've proven what I've just done works...
我若活著證明了我的理論
In which case, ha, I won.
如果是這樣我就贏了
Or I'm dead
或是我死了
and I'd like you to know that it's all your fault. It really is, you know.
我想讓你知道，這全是你的錯
You drove me to this.
是你逼我的
In which case, ha, I also won.
所以我，還是贏了
Sort of.
精神上啦
I'm going in in three...
倒數後開始，三
two...
二
one.
一
Hah!
嘿
Newton. Newton!
牛頓，牛頓
What have you done
你幹了什麼好事
Gipsy Danger neural test commencing in 20 minutes.
吉普賽危機神經測試二十分鍾後開始
May I come in, Mako
我可以進來嗎，真子
All pilots report to mess hall.
所有駕駛員到大廳集合
A long time ago,
很久以前
I made you a promise.
我對你許下承諾
準備好
These transmitters are non-operative.
這些發射器壞了
(吉普賽危機初步試驗
八時整)
I need them replaced.
趕快更新
Setting harness for test mode.
背帶設定為測驗模式
Waiting for second pilot.
等候副駕駛
Two pilots onboard.
正副駕駛到齊
I'm gonna take this side if you don't mind.
不介意的話我要選這邊
My left arm's kinda shot.
我左手受過傷
Sure.
當然
Are you gonna say anything
你要說什麼嗎
No point.
沒必要
In five minutes you're gonna be inside my head.
五分鍾後你會進入我的大腦
You look good.
你看起來真棒
Pilots onboard and ready to connect.
駕駛就位，準備進行聯結
Prepare for neural handshake.
準備進行神經握合
Initiating neural handshake.
神經握合開始
Okey.
好的
We're not in the simulator now, Mako.
真子，這次可不是模擬器
Remember, don't chase the rabbit.
記住，不要走火入魔
Random access brain impulse triggers.
提防隨機擷取大腦脈衝刺激
Memories.
那些回憶
Just let 'em flow, don't latch on.
讓它湧現，不要被吸進去
Tune 'em out. Stay in the drift.
別理它，專心維持浮動聯結
The drift is silence.
浮動聯結是平靜無聲的
Neural interface drift initiated.
開始神經介面浮動聯結
Look, Raleigh! Over there!
萊利，往那邊看
Mama!
媽媽
Raleigh, listen to me!
萊利，聽我說
Right hemisphere calibrated.
右大腦半球校準完成
Left hemisphere calibrated.
左大腦半球校準完成
Ready to activate the Jaeger.
準備好啟動機甲獵人
Okay, Gipsy. Lining up nicely.
好了，吉普賽，聯結非常成功
Better get ready.
好戲要上場了
Pilot to Jaeger connection complete.
駕駛對機甲獵人聯結完成
Marshal! Marshal!
元帥元帥
I need to talk to you.
我有急事找你
Not now, Mr. Gottlieb.
現在不行，葛裡布先生
I'm sure you can appreciate how important this moment is to me.
相信你明白此刻對我多重要
Newton created a neural bridge from garbage and drifted with a Kaiju.
牛頓用舊器材打造神經橋，和怪獸進行浮動聯結
I found him prone, and...
他本來昏倒在地
he's sort of dazed.
現在有點恍神
I don't exactly know what to do.
我不知該如何處理
I told you it would work.
我跟你說過會管用
Yes, you did.
是的，你說過
Well, what'd you see
所以你看到什麼
You know, it was only a fragment of a brain,
我只用了怪獸大腦的部分
so really all I was able to get was, like,
所以只能看到…
a series of, uh,
一系列的
images or... or impressions.
影像或...印記
You know Like when you blink your eyes over and over and over again
就像你眨眼太多次
all you really see are, like, frames. Um...
就只能看到片段畫面
it was emotional in the...
情感...
Newton.
牛頓
Okay, Newton.
好了，牛頓
It was so...
太衝擊了....
Newton, look at me.
牛頓，看著我
Now I want you to take your time
我要你慢慢來
and be very specific.
講明確點
Okay.
好
Well, I don't feel like they're just...
我不覺得他們是
following some sort of animalistic urge,
為了獸性的衝動
you know, just hunting and gathering.
像是狩獵和採集
And I think they're attacking us under orders.
我覺得他們是奉命攻擊我們
That's impossible.
不可能
- Is that impossible - It's impossible.
-為何不可能
-就是不可能
Because...
因為…
You know what Why don't you drift with a kaiju
不如，你來試試跟怪獸浮動聯結
You! Shut up!
你閉嘴！
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
You,
你
keep talking.
繼續說
These beings, these masters,
這些東西，怪獸的主人
they're colonists.
他們是殖民主義者
They overtake worlds. They just...
他們占領世界
they just consume them and then... then, they move on to the next.
吃乾抹淨後就移往下一個地方
And they've been here before in sort of a trial run.
他們以前來這裡探勘過
It was the dinosaurs.
就在恐龍時期
But the atmosphere wasn't conducive, right
但當時大氣組成不適合居住
So they waited it out. And they waited it out.
所以他們靜候良機
And now, you know,
現在
with ozone depletion, and carbon monoxide, polluted waters ...
現在臭氧稀薄，一氧化碳大增，水質汙染
well, we've practically terraformed it for them.
我們替他們再造生活環境
Cause now they're coming back, and it's perfect.
他們要回來，因為現在一切完美
See, the first wave, that was just the hounds.
第一波攻擊只是偵查走狗
Categories 1 through 4, it was nothing.
第一到第四量級根本不算什麼
Their sole purpose was to aim for the populated areas and take out the vermin... us!
主要目的是攻擊人口密集地區
把我們這些害蟲趕盡殺絕
The second wave, that is the exterminators.
第二波是終結者
And they will finish the job.
他們不會留活口
And then,
到時候
the new tenants will take possession.
新房客就會搬進來了
See, the reason that I found the identical DNA in the two separate Kaiju organs
那兩隻怪獸之所以有相同DNA
is because they are grown!
是因為他們是培育出來的
Newton, I need you to do it again.
牛頓，我需要你再來一次
I need more information.
我需要更多資訊
I can't... I can't do it again.
我無法再來一次
I... I mean, not unless you have a fresh Kaiju brain lying around.
除非你有私房的新鮮怪獸大腦
Do you
你有嗎
Pretty impressive.
挺厲害的
Yeah, he remembers how to turn it on.
對，他還記得怎麼開機
Boy,
喂
show some respect.
你放尊重點
When his brother died, he got the Jaeger back to shore on his own.
他哥哥死後，他獨自將機甲獵人帶回岸邊
I've known one other pilot's been able to do that.
只有另一個駕駛成功辦到過
Now, there are certain individuals
有個人專門經營
whose business is the preservation and exploitation of Kaiju remains.
怪獸屍體的買賣
Yeah, right, Em...
對...
black market dealers, right
黑市商人，對嗎
Yep. They're in and out in a matter of hours.
對，他們逗留現場數小時
They neutralize the acidic factor of the blood,
中和血液中的酸性物質
and they harvest what they need.
摘走他們想要的部位
Now, this guy,
這個傢伙是
this is Hannibal Chau.
漢尼拔周
He runs the Kaiju black market here in Asia.
他經營亞洲的怪獸黑市
When our funding ran out,
我們資金用完後
we turned to him for help,
去找他贊助
and in return, I gave him exclusive rights to all Kaiju remains in the region.
交換條件是把此區的，怪獸遺骸獨家提供給他
You did that
是你授權的啊
Last days of war, gentlemen.
這是權宜之計，兩位
Go to the corner of Fong and Tull.
去芳路和圖街的交叉口
Show them that card. Look for that symbol.
把卡片給他們，尋找那個標誌
And a word to the wise,
給句忠告
do not trust him.
不要相信他
Calibration complete.
校準完成
The hull!
機艙
It went through the hull!
他劃破機艙了
Raleigh, listen to me!
萊利，聽我說
You need...
你需要…
Pilot out of alignment.
駕駛連線斷裂
Both out of alignment.
兩人的連線都斷裂了
Both of them
兩個都是嗎
Both of them.
兩個都是
Gipsy, Gipsy!
吉普賽，吉普賽
You're out of alignment!
你們連線斷裂了
You are both...
你們的連線都斷裂了
I'm okay. Just let me control it.
我沒事，我已控制住了
You're stabilizing. But Mako is way out.
你已穩定，但真子可不妙
Mako.
真子
She's starting to chase the rabbit!
她開始走火入魔了
Mako, don't get stuck in a memory.
真子，別被回憶牽著走
Stay with me.
跟我一起
Stay in the now.
留在此刻
Don't engage in a memory.
別陷入回憶中
Mako.
真子
Mako!
Listen to me.
聽我說
Mako
真子
Mama!
媽媽
Mako.
真子
This is just a memory.
這只是回憶
None of this is real.
這些都不是真的
Weapons system engaged.
武器系統啟動
Plasma Cannon powering up.
準備發射等離子炮
Oh, no.
糟了
Weapon system engaged!
武器系統啟動
Go to fail-safe!
切換故障安全防護裝置
Fail-safe is not responding.
防護裝置沒有回應
There's a problem with the neural blocker!
神經阻隔器出了問題
Her connection's way too strong!
她的聯結太強大了
Fully charged.
裝載完成
Mako!
真子
Mako, listen to me.
真子，聽我說
This is just a memory.
這只是回憶
None of it is real.
不是真的
大家快撤離，快點
The power line! The power line!
電源線電源線
Get the main power line!
把主電源線拔掉
Take them offline! Take them offline!
切斷他們的電源切斷他們的電源
I just did.
切斷了
Weapon system disengaged.
武器系統關閉
Mako!
真子
Neural bridge exercise invalid.
神經橋演習取消
It's okay.
沒事了
Drift sequence terminated.
浮動聯結步驟中止
(黑貨貧民窟，香港)
Hello.
你好啊
You looking for some Kaiju bone powder
你想買怪獸骨粉嗎
S... some bone...
骨粉
Some bone powder
怪獸骨粉
Uh, no,
沒有
why would I want that
要那個幹嘛
Male potency.
增進男性雄風
I take it myself.
我自己也吃
I see.
這樣啊
Uh, no, thank you.
不用了，多謝
I'm looking for Hannibal Chau.
我找漢尼拔周
Come.
過來
Hannibal Chau, huh
漢尼拔周是吧
Good luck.
祝你好運
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Oh, my God, this place is heaven!
我的天啊，這裡是天堂
That's a lymph gland from a category 2!
那是第二量級的淋巴結
And what are you working on here
你在幹什麼
Is this a cuticle In mint condition
這是保存完整的角質層嗎
Is that a Kaiju skin parasite
那是怪獸的表皮寄生蟲嗎
I've never seen them alive before!
我從沒看過活的
They... they usually die as soon as the Kaiju falls!
他們通常跟怪獸一起死去
I thought you couldn't keep them alive!
我以為他們無法獨自存活
You can if you soak 'em in ammonia.
把他們浸在阿摩尼亞裡就可以
What do you want
你想幹嘛
I'm looking for Hannibal Chau.
我要找漢尼拔周，我聽說
I was told he was here.
他在這裡
Who wants to know
你聽誰說的
I really can't say.
我不能說
Stacker pentecost sent me!
是史塔克潘塔考斯特派我來的
Oh, that's great.
好極了
That's real great.
So I take it you're Hannibal Chau, right
我猜你就是漢尼拔周吧
You like the name
喜歡這名字嗎
I took it from, uh...
取自…
my favorite historical character
我最愛的歷史人物
and my second-favorite szechuan restaurant in Brooklyn.
和第二愛在布魯克林的四川餐廳拼湊出來的名字
Now tell me what you want,
說出你來此的目的
before I gut you like a pig and feed you to the skin louse.
不然把你宰了餵寄生蟲
She can't control her drift,
她不能控制浮動聯結
and he went out of phase first!
而且是他先脫離介面
We all know what happened.
我們都知道
We can't afford mistakes,
我們不能承擔出錯的風險
the Kaiju keep evolving,
怪獸不斷進化
they keep kicking our asses!
擊敗我們
He's a has... been,
他過氣了
she's a rookie.
她又是菜鳥
I don't want them protecting my bomb run,
我不要他們掩護我的炸彈行動
sir
長官
You need to watch your tone, Mr. Hansen.
注意你的語氣，韓森先生
Hey, stay there.
喂，待在那裡
Give me a moment.
等我一下
You two are a goddamn disgrace.
你們兩個真是可恥
You're gonna get us all killed,
你們會害死大家
and here's the thing, Raleigh
重點是，萊利
I want to come back from this mission
我還想活著完成任務
'cause I quite like my life.
因為我很喜歡我的人生
So why don't you...
拜託你幫大家一個忙
just do us all a favor and disappear
自動消失吧
It's the only thing you're good at.
反正你只擅長那點
Stop! Now!
給我閉嘴
Yeah, that's right.
對，沒錯
You just hold back your little girlfriend.
管好你的小馬子
One of you bitches needs a leash.
把這小賤人用鏈子栓好
Apologize to her.
跟她道歉
Screw you.
去死吧
I said,
我叫
apologize to her.
你跟她道歉
What's going on
怎麼回事
On your feet, both of you!
立刻站好，你們兩個
Becket, Mori,
貝克特、森
into my office, now.
到我辦公室
This is over!
住手
You're a ranger.
你是個突擊隊員
For christ sake.
看在老天的份上
Why don't you start acting like one
注意你的舉止
I went out of phase first.
是我先脫離介面
It was my mistake.
是我的錯
No.
不
It was my mistake.
這是我的錯
I should have never let you two in the same machine.
我不該讓你們駕駛同一架機械
So, what
所以，現在
You're grounding us
你要禁止我們駕駛嗎
Not you.
不是你
Permission to be dismissed, sir.
請求准許離開，長官
Permission granted, Miss Mori.
請求獲准，森小姐
Mako.
真子
Sir, what are you doing
長官，你在做什麼
She is the strongest candidate by far.
她是最強的候選人
What other options do we have
我們還有什麼其他選擇
Tell me!
告訴我
Do not let my calm demeanor fool you, ranger!
不要讓我冷靜的態度騙了你，突擊隊員
Now is not a good moment for your insubordination!
現在不是以下犯上的好時機
Mako is too inexperienced to rein in her memories during combat.
真子的經驗不足，無法在作戰時控制自己情緒
That's not why you grounded her.
這不是你禁止她的原因
I was in her memories.
我在她回憶裡
I saw everything.
我什麼都看到了
I don't care what you think you saw.
我不在乎你自以為看到了什麼
I know what she means to you.
我知道她對你的意義
I saw it! I...
我看到了
Hey! Hey!
嘿嘿
This conversation is over.
這段對話結束了
Marshal.
元帥
Marshal, can we just talk about this for one second!
元帥，能不能討論一下這件事
You rescued her.
你救了她
You raised her.
養大她
You're not protecting her now.
你現在不是在保護她
You are holding her back.
你是在遏止她
One,
第一
Don't you ever touch me again.
永遠別再碰我
Two,
第二
Don't you ever touch me again.
永遠別再碰我
Now, you have no idea who the hell I am
你不知道我是誰
or where I've come from,
或是經歷過什麼
and I'm not about to tell you my whole life story.
我也沒空告訴你我的人生經歷
All I need to be to you and everybody in this dome is a fixed point.
你們只需要知道我是這裡的老大
The last man standing.
永不放棄的鬥士
I do not need your sympathy or your admiration.
我不需要你的同情或敬佩
All I need is your compliance,
我只需要你的服從
and your fighting skills.
和戰鬥技巧
And if I can't get that,
如果你做不到
then you can go back to the wall that I found you crawling on.
就爬回我找到你的那個狗洞
Do I make myself clear
我說得夠清楚了嗎
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
Good.
很好
I'm sorry.
對不起
I should've warned you.
我該先警告你的
First drifts are rough.
第一次浮動聯結特別困難
But you weren't just tapping into my memories.
但你不只切入我的回憶
You were tapping into my brother's too.
也切入我哥哥的回憶中
When yancy was taken, we were still connected.
當楊希被抓走時，我們仍相連
I felt his fear, his pain, his helplessness, and then...
我感覺到他的恐懼、痛苦、無助，然後
He was gone.
他消失了
I felt it.
我感覺到了
I know.
我知道
You know, you live in someone else's head for so long
當你在別人腦袋中生活這麼久
the hardest part to deal with is the silence.
最難面對的是寂靜無聲
To let someone else in, to really connect,
讓別人進入，真正聯結
you have to trust them.
你必須相信他們
And today the drift was strong.
今天的浮動聯結很強
Her heart.
她的心臟
When's the last time you saw it
你最後一次看到是什麼時候
In a long time.
很久以前
Movement in the breach.
突破點有動靜
Double event.
兩起活動
Two signatures.
兩個讀數
Dilation indicator,
擴張指數顯示
category 4.
第四量級
Excuse me.
借過
The breach was exposed at 23:00 hours.
23點整時突破點外露了
We have two signatures,
我們有兩個讀數
both category 4s.
都是第四量級
Code names:
代號：
Otachi and Leatherback.
鐵尾和革龜
They'll reach Hong Kong within the hour.
會在一個小時內抵達香港
Evacuate the city.
疏散城市
Shut down the Bridges.
關閉橋樑
I want every single civilian in a refuge right now.
我要每個市民都去避難所
Crimson Typhoon,
暴風赤紅
Cherno Alpha,
車諾艾爾發
I want you to frontline the harbor.
我要你們坐鎮港口前線
Stay on the Miracle Mile.
守住黃金海岸線
Striker, I want you to stay back,
衝鋒號，你們擔任後衛
look after the coastline.
看守沿岸地區
We cannot afford to lose you,
我們不能失去你們
so only engage as a final option.
除非萬不得已不要出手
Yes, sir!
-是的，長官
You two.
你們兩個
You stay put.
待在這裡
Let's go!
走吧
Loccent, Striker's got the ball and we're on the roll.
任務控制室，衝鋒號出發了，目前一切順利
Loccent.
任務控制室
Near positions and awaiting your orders.
即將抵達崗位等候命令
Remain in the Miracle Mile.
駐守黃金海岸線
Engage at your discretion.
除非必要，不得出手
Guys, keep your eyes open.
各位，謹慎行事
These category 4s are the biggest we've ever seen, both in size and weight.
這些第四量級的尺寸和噸位前所未見
Cherno Alpha reaching target zone.
車諾艾爾發抵達目標區域
Disengaging transport.
脫離運輸機
Cherno Alpha in position. Miracle mile.
車諾艾爾發抵達黃金海岸線崗位
Cherno Alpha holding the coastline.
車諾艾爾發鎮守海岸線
Beacon is on.
開啟燈塔
Look at 'em.
你看他們
They believe the Kaiju are sent from heaven.
他們認為怪獸是上天派來的
That the gods are expressing their displeasure with our behavior.
是老天對我們不滿的徵兆
The silly bastards.
那些蠢蛋
And what do you believe
那你覺得呢
Well...
這個嘛…
I believe that Kaiju bone powder is 500 bucks a pound.
我覺得怪獸骨粉值五百元一磅
What do you want
你到底想幹嘛
I need to access a Kaiju brain.
我需要一顆完好的怪獸大腦
Completely intact.
不可能
No, no, no.
不，不，不
The skull plate is so dense
他們頭骨太厚了
that by the time you drill into it...
等我們鑿穿後
the brain's rotted away.
大腦早爛掉了
But I'm talking about the secondary brain.
但我說的是次要大腦
Now we both know
我們都知道
that the Kaiju are so large
怪獸這麼大隻
they need two brains to move around, like a dinosaur.
他們需要兩個大腦來控制行動，就像恐龍那樣
I want to get my hands on that.
我得拿到一個
What the hell do you want a secondary brain for, anyway
你要次要大腦幹嘛
I mean, every part of the Kaiju sells.
怪獸的每個部位都能賣
Cartilage, spleen, liver.
軟骨、脾臟、肝臟
Even the crap!
甚至大便都能賣
One cubic meter of crap
一立方米怪獸大便
has enough phosphorous in it
含有足夠的磷
to fertilize a whole field!
可以給一整座田施肥
But the brain...
但是大腦
Too much ammonia.
太多阿摩尼亞了
So what's the deal, little fella
所以你想拿它幹嘛，小兄弟
Well, that's classified.
那是機密
So I couldn't tell you.
距離地面五萬英尺
Even if I wanted to.
就算我想告訴你也不能說
But it is pretty cool.
但這事很酷
So I might tell you.
所以我可能會告訴你
I'm gonna tell you.
我就告訴你吧
I figured out how to drift with a Kaiju.
我找出跟怪獸浮動聯結的方法了
Are you funnin' me son
你是在開玩笑嗎
It's fascinating how their minds work.
他們大腦的運作方式很有趣
Every single Kaiju, his mind's connected.
每隻怪獸的大腦都是相連的
The species has like a...
這個物種有蜂巢般的
like a hive mind.
聯合大腦
Holy Jesus.
老天爺啊
You've gone and done it, haven't you
你已經試過了，對不對
I did it a little bit, yeah.
我小試了一下身手
You goddamn moron.
你這個死白癡
(從右邊，三點鍾)
(三點鍾)
(雷雲陣式，準備)
Loccent! Typhoon and Alpha are in trouble.
控制室，暴風和艾爾發有麻煩
We're movin' in!
我們去幫忙
You are to hold your ground.
你們要堅守陣地
Do not engage.
不要介入
We need you to carry that bomb.
我們需要你們運送炸彈
Do you copy
收到了嗎
Jesus, we can't just sit here and watch 'em die.
老天，我們不能坐視他們被屠殺
Come on!
上啊
Ah, screw this.
去他的
Loccent, we're movin' in now!
控制室，我們要出手了
(暴風倒下了)
(我們殺了那個渾蛋)
Cherno Alpha, we've been hit with some type of acid!
車諾艾爾發受到某種強酸攻擊
Come on!
快點
Hull has been compromised.
機艙被穿透了
We need backup immediately!
我們需要立即的協助
Just hold on, Cherno! We're on our way!
堅持住，車諾，我們正趕來
(海水滲入反應爐了)
Our power move! Yeah!
我們的招牌必殺技
We just lost Cherno, sir.
我們失去車諾了，長官
Engaging air missiles!
啟動空中飛彈
What's going on
怎麼回事
What happened
發生什麼事了
The blast. It jumbled all the jaegers' electrical circuits.
電磁波破壞了機甲獵人的電路
What the hell was that
那是什麼鬼玩意
Loccent!
任務控制室
I've never seen that before.
以前從沒看過
Loccent!
任務控制室
They're adapting.
他們在進化
This isn't a defense mechanism, it's a weapon!
那不是防禦機制，而是武器
Get me Striker!
讓我跟衝鋒號通話
Nothing, sir. The mark 5's digital's fried.
沒辦法，長官，第五代的數位系統失靈
It'll take me two hours to reroute the auxiliary.
轉接到備用系統要兩小時
All the jaegers, they're digital!
所有機甲獵人都是數位系統
Not all of them, Marshal.
不是所有的，元帥
Gipsy's analog. Nuclear.
吉普賽使用類比系統，核能動力
We got two Kaijus.
兩隻怪獸來襲
We gotta get out.
我們得快閃，這邊走
Hang on a second. Excuse me.
等等，抱歉
Wh-what's going on
怎麼回事
There are two goddamn Kaiju headed straight for Hong Kong city.
有兩隻怪獸直撲香港
No, no, no. That's not possible.
不，不可能
There's never been two before.
從沒一次出現兩隻過
Well, maybe
或許是因為
that's 'cause nobody ever drifted with one before, eh,
以前沒人跟他們浮動聯結
genius!
天才
When jaeger pilots drift,
當機甲獵人駕駛浮動聯結
it's a two-way street.
那是雙向的
A bridge, right
一個橋樑，對嗎
It sets up a connection.
那是一種連通
Both ways!
雙向交流
"A hive mentality," You said!
你也說他們有共通的蜂巢大腦
Maybe those Kaiju are tryin' to find you.
或許那些怪獸是來找你的
What... what're we gonna do
那我們該怎麼辦
I'm gonna wait out this shitstorm in my own private Kaiju bunker.
我要去私人的怪獸避難所，等到風平浪靜再出來
But you are going to a public refuge.
但你得去公家避難所
I tried it once.
我以前試過一次
once
僅此一次
Now get the hell outta here.
現在給我滾出去
Move! Move! I'm a doctor! I'm a doctor!
借過借過，我是醫生
Okay, hold on. Let me in.
等等，讓我進去
Okay, I'm a doctor.
我是醫生
Okay, let me in, I'm a doctor.
我是醫生，讓我進去
There's no emergency power.
沒有緊急電源
We gotta bail.
我們得閃人
I'm gonna try somethin' else.
我要來試點別的
No! Don't disengage!
不不要脫下肩帶
My arm!
我的手臂
Come on! Get on your feet, old man!
快站起來，老頭
Don't call me that!
別叫我老頭
He's right outside.
他就在外面
We gotta get outta here now!
我們得離開這裡
We're not goin' anywhere!
我們哪也不去
Now you and I are the only thing standin' between that ugly bastard and a city of 2 million people.
我們是那醜八怪，和一千萬市民間的唯一防線
Now we have a choice here.
我們有選擇
We either sit and wait
是要坐以待斃
or we take these flare guns and do something really stupid.
或是拿這些信號槍去做些蠢事
How's your arm
你的手臂如何
Ah, just give me the gun.
把槍給我
Hey, you!
嘿，就是你
I think we just pissed it off!
我想我們惹毛他了
All right, Mako.
好了，真子
Get ready, this is for real!
準備好，這次是來真的
Yeah!
好耶
Come on, Gipsy!
快啊，吉普賽
Kick his ass!
打趴他
Come on!
來吧
Let's do this! Together!
我們一起上
Elbow rocket!
肘部火箭
Now!
現在
Hang on, Mako!
堅持住，真子
Plasma Cannon,
等離子炮
now!
現在
Plasma Cannon engaged.
啟動等離子炮
Empty the clip!
清空這個彈匣
Wait.
等等
I think this guy's dead.
我想這傢伙掛了
But...
但...
let's check for a pulse.
還是檢查一下脈搏
Okay.
好
No pulse.
沒有脈搏
He stopped right above us.
他停在我們上頭
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
This isn't a refuge. This is...
這不是避難所
this is a buffet line!
這裡是吃到飽餐廳
He knows I'm here.
他知道我在這裡
He knows I'm here!
He knows we're all here!
他知道我在這裡
No, you don't understand, he's trying to get me!
你不懂，他是來抓我的
He knows I'm here and he's trying to get me!
他是來抓我的，他知道我在這裡
(怪獸要他，他是要他的)
What was that What did you say!
她說什麼我得出去
(怪獸要他，他是要他的)
What was she saying!
她說什麼!
I gotta get out of here!
我得出去
Let me out of here! I got...
讓我出去
I got... ah, come on!
拜託
Those were expensive glasses.
那副眼鏡很貴耶
This is the worst.
這太糟糕了
Torque engaged.
啟動扭力
I can't pinpoint it.
我無法確認位置
It's movin' quick.
他移動得太快
Keep your eyes open.
小心行事
Choppers, do you have a visual Over.
直升機，能看到怪獸嗎完畢
Come on!
挺住
I'll hold it!
我來抵擋他
Vent the coolant on the left flank!
把左側的冷卻液排出
Coolant venting.
排出冷卻液
Co2 purge.
二氧化碳沖放
Venting coolant.
冷卻液排出
Atmosphere loss in progress.
逐漸脫離大氣層
Temperature's droppin'!
溫度下降
We're losing oxygen!
我們氧氣要不夠了
Both plasma cannons are shot.
兩座等離子炮都毀了
We're out of options, Mako.
我們玩完了，真子
不，我們還有最後絕招
Sword deployment.
釋出屠獸劍
為我家人復仇
Altitude actuation off-balance.
高度推動失衡
50,000 feet to ground contact.
距離地面五萬英尺
Look, there!
你們看，在那裡
Altitude loss critical.
嚴重失速
40,000 feet.
四萬英尺
Gipsy,
吉普賽
listen to me!
聽我說
Loosen all the shock absorbers,
調大避震器
use your gyroscope as balance and ball up!
用回轉儀平衡，抱好頭手
It's your only chance!
這是唯一生機
20,000 feet.
兩萬英尺
Fuel purge!
燃料沖放
Now!
現在
Impact alert.
撞擊警告
We're comin' in too fast.
我們速度太快了
We're comin' in too fast. Brace for impact, Mako...
我們速度太快了，準備好，真子
Mako,
真子
talk to me.
說話啊
Mako,
真子
you okay
你還好嗎
Yeah.
還好
You
你呢
Go to Dr. Geiszler now!
去找蓋斯勒博士
Yes, sir!
是的，長官
I want the two remaining Jaegers back to 100% functionality.
把倖存的兩架機甲獵人恢復到百分之百的戰力
Yes, sir!
是的，長官
We're gonna harvest
我們要摘除
the skin, the talons and the wing.
皮膚、爪子和翅膀
Germans are gonna go nuts for that stuff.
德國人會愛死這些東西
Let me see that map.
地圖給我瞧瞧
Here is where the Kaiju fell,
怪獸死在這裡
here's where we concentrate our efforts.
我們集中火力在這裡開工
We'll get it, boss.
我們會搞定，老板
Right.
很好
Hey
嘿
Okay,
好
guess who's back, you one-eyed bitch
看看是誰回來了，你這個獨眼龍
And you owe me a Kaiju brain.
你欠我一顆怪獸大腦
Raleigh!
萊利
My kid'd never admit it...
我兒子絕對不會承認
but he's grateful.
但他很感激你們
We both are.
我們都很感激
Mr. Becket!
貝克特先生
Miss Mori!
森小姐
In all of my years fighting...
我作戰多年以來
I've never...
我從沒有
seen...
見過
anything like that.
這樣的表現
Well done.
幹得好
Proud of you.
以你們為傲
Proud of us all.
以我們所有人為傲
But...
但是
as harsh as it sounds,
這雖聽起來殘忍
there is no time to celebrate.
我們沒有時間慶祝
We lost two crews.
我們失去了兩組戰友
No time to grieve.
卻沒時間哀悼
Reset that clock.
把戰鬥鍾歸零
Reset the clock.
I still can't believe what you did to me.
我還是不敢相信你這樣狠心
I mean, I coulda been eaten.
害我差點被吃掉
Well, that was definitely the plan.
我是依計行事
Lucky for you, that didn't become necessary, huh
算你好運，沒被一口吃掉
Thank you so much. You're so kind.
感恩了，你人真好
I really appreciate all of this.
我真是感激涕零
But now do you mind tellin' me exactly what is taking so long for your workers to get that brain
你手下怎麼搞這麼久，還沒弄到大腦
Well, they...
他們
pump the cavity full of CO2,
要在怪獸體內灌入二氧化碳
just like in any other laparoscopic surgery.
就像腹腔鏡手術那樣
Okay, yes, obviously,
那是當然
the CO2's gonna delay the acidic reaction, yes.
二氧化碳能減緩酸蝕作用
And it allows us to harvest.
讓我們能摘除器官
But our boys need oxygen pumped into their suits.
隔離衣也得灌氧氣
They move slow.
那會導致他們動作遲緩
What's goin' on in there, boys
裡面情況如何
We've reached...
我們到了
the upper pelvic area.
上骨盆區
Moving to the 25th vertebra.
往第25節脊椎骨移動
Even through the suit, boss,
就算穿著隔離衣
it smells like dead catfish in here.
這裡聞起來還是像死魚
Boss.
老闆
The secondary brain...
這個次要大腦
is damage.
損壞了
It's ruin.
不能用了
Fuck!
該死
How could they screw that up!
這種事也能搞砸
Wait. Wait.
等等
What was that
怎麼回事
Did he say "Wait" Why wait
為什麼要等等
Do you hear that
你有聽到嗎
It's like a heartbeat.
聽起來像心跳
Oh, my God.
老天
Oh, my God, this can't be. Hold on a second.
不可能，等一下
Hey!
嘿
Let me have that!
對講機還我
Shh, shh!
噓，噓
Listen, listen!
你聽，你聽
Listen to this.
你聽聽看
It's pregnant.
他懷孕了
No, no!
不，不要
Please. Please.
拜託
No! No.
不不
I knew it.
我就知道
Gone.
掛了
His lungs weren't fully formed.
他的肺部還沒發育完全
Umbilical cord tied around his neck.
臍帶纏繞住脖子
No way he could survive outside the womb for...
在子宮外無法存活
more than a minute.
超過一分鍾
One look, that's all I needed. I knew he wouldn't make it.
看一眼，我就知道他死定了
Ugly little bastard.
醜陋的小屁孩
Anyway, I woulda...
總之，我會…
How sick are you
你病得多重
And why didn't you tell me
為何不告訴我
What's to tell
有什麼好說的
You know, them mark 1s,
第一代
we scraped them bad boys together in 14 months.
十四個月倉促打造成軍
Last thing we were thinking about was radiation shielding.
沒人想過要加裝輻射防護罩
I ran nearly a dozen missions.
我執行了快一打任務
I stayed under the medical radar for awhile, but...
病情初期沒被察覺
the last time I jockeyed was Tokyo.
最後一次駕駛機甲獵人在東京
I finished the fight solo,
我獨自一人完成任務
but for three hours...
但三小時的過程
I burned.
造成輻射過量
They warned me if I ever stepped foot into a jaeger again,
他們警告我若再踏入機甲獵人
the toll would be too much.
後果足以致命
You and I are the only two that ever ran solo combat.
只有你我兩人曾單獨完成任務
That's why I brought you here.
所以我把你找回來
What is it
什麼事
Sir, it's happening.
長官，來了
I just got two signatures with unprecedented dilation,
我剛收到兩個讀數和超高擴張
40-meter spikes.
大約四十公尺
What category
什麼量級
Checking the ratios, category four.
根據比例，第四量級
Where're they headed
往哪前進
That's the thing, they're not headin' anywhere.
奇怪的是他們沒有離開
They're hovering just above the breach.
只是在突破點上盤旋
It's...
好像...
it's like they're protecting it or something.
在保護什麼
All right, Gipsy... Striker, on deck.
讓吉普賽和衝鋒號備戰
Sir, Herc cannot ride.
長官，赫克無法駕駛
His arm...
他的手臂
You heard me.
你聽到我的命令了
Two signatures.
兩個讀數
Two! There are...
兩個!
there are two Kaiju signatures in the breach,
突破點有兩個怪獸生命讀數
not three like I predicted!
而不是如預測的三個
Hermann! I haven't exactly had a very good day, okay!
賀曼我今天沒心情聽你唸
I got about 5 minutes...
我只有五分鍾
Should be three Kaijus.
應該有三隻
before brain death occurs here!
不然大腦就要壞死了
I don't wanna spend it talking about your theories!
我沒空鳥你的理論
This is all wrong!
這全錯了
There should be three Kaijus coming through,
這次該有三隻怪獸
not two!
而不是兩隻
There should be three and there's two
三隻而不是二隻
I'm sorry, it hurts to be wrong, - doesn't it, Hermann，- I am not wrong,
- 我瞭承認錯誤很難受，是吧，賀曼
- 我才沒錯
but there is something here that we don't understand.
但有些事我們還沒搞懂
Okay. Hermann,
好，賀曼
hopefully we can argue about any mistakes
來日若有空再來吵
you made in your predictive model in the future!
你預測模式的缺失
But in the meantime,
但現在神經元介面
the neural interface is way off the charts!
已經破表
If you want to help, help with that!
若想幫忙請自便
Newton, I am not wrong.
牛頓，我才沒錯
There is only one way to make sure...
只有一個辦法可以確認
and that is to do this...
那就是我倆
together.
一起來
I'll go with you.
我跟你攜手
That's what the jaeger pilots do,
機甲獵人駕駛也是這樣做
share the neural load.
分享神經元負荷
You're serious
你說真的嗎
You... you would do that for me
你願意為我這麼做
Or... you would do that with me
或是說你願意和我一起
Well, with worldwide destruction a certain alternative...
反正世界都要毀了
Do I really have a choice
我有選擇嗎
Then say it with me, my man.
那跟我一起說，我的朋友：
"We're gonna own this bad boy!"
「我們要征服這個壞蛋」
By Jove, we are going to own this thing for sure!
我對天發誓，我們一定要征服這玩意
Oi, Tendo.
天同
Tendo!
You're not suited up.
你沒穿上裝備
Yeah, I'm aware of that, Elvis.
我當然知道，貓王
I need to know what's going on.
我要知道現在是什麼情況
He said suit up, so suit up.
叫你著裝你就著裝吧
Tendo, I can't pilot Striker on my own, now, can I!
我無法一人駕駛衝鋒號
Dad's hurt,
老爸受傷了
so who's gonna be my copilot
誰來擔任我的副駕駛
I don't remember it being so tight.
我不記得駕駛服有這麼緊
Getting back into that Jaeger will kill you.
再駕駛機甲獵人你會沒命
Not gettin' into one would kill us all.
不駕駛的話大家都沒命
Listen,
聽我說
you are a brave girl.
你是個勇敢的女孩
I'm so lucky to have seen you grow.
我很幸運能看著你長大
But if I'm going to do this...
但如果想完成任務
I need you to protect me.
我需要你來保護我
Can you do that
你做得到嗎
Everyone, listen up!
各位，大家聽好
Today...
今天...
at the edge of our hope...
站在我們希望的邊緣
at the end of our time...
處在我們時代的尾端
we have chosen not only to believe in ourselves,
我們選擇不只信任自己
but in each other.
還要信任彼此
Today there's not a man nor woman in here that shall stand alone.
今天站在這裡的男女老幼都不需孤軍奮戰
Not today.
今天不用
Today we face the monsters that are at our door
今天我們迎戰前來挑釁的怪獸
and bring the fight to them!
我們主動出擊
Today we are canceling the apocalypse!
今天我們將終結末日
Go to the safety zone right now.
現在往安全區域移動
Hey, Marshal!
元帥
You know, that was a great speech,
很棒的演說
but how exactly are you and I supposed to match up in there
但我們在裡面要如何合作
I carry nothing into the drift.
我不會把任何東西帶入浮動聯結
No memories, no fear.
沒有回憶，沒有恐懼
No rank.
沒有官階
And as for you...
至於你
well, you're easy.
你這個人很簡單
You're an egotistical jerk with daddy issues.
你是個有父親情節的狂妄小屁孩
A simple puzzle I solved on day one.
我第一天就看穿你了
But you are your father's son...
但是虎父無犬子
so we'll drift just fine.
所以我倆聯結沒問題
Works for me.
我同意
Hey, now.
聽我說
When you drift with someone,
當你常和某人浮動聯結時
you feel like there's nothing to talk about.
你會覺得跟那人無需多言
I just don't want to regret all the things that I never said out loud.
我只是怕以後會後悔沒說出口
Don't.
不要
You don't need to.
不需要說
I know them all.
我都知道
I always have.
我一直都知道
Hey. Hey, handsome.
嗨，小帥哥
Oh, I'm gonna miss you.
我會很想念你
You look after him for me.
幫我照顧他
Stacker.
史塔克
That's my son you got there.
我把兒子托付給你
My son.
我的兒子
You know, Mako,
真子
all those years I spent livin' in the past,
這些年我都活在過去
I never really thought about the future.
我從沒仔細想過未來
Until now.
直到現在
I never did have very good timing.
我總是抓錯時機
You ready for this
你準備好了嗎
Oh, yes, yes.
好了
Initiating neural handshake
準備開始神經握合
in Five...
五
Four...
四
Three...
三
Two...
二...
One
一
Are you okay
你還好嗎
Yes, of course.
是的，當然
I'm completely fine.
我完全沒事
The drift.
浮動聯結
You saw it
你看到了吧
Yeah.
對
Did you
看到了嗎
Listen, we have to warn them.
聽好，我們得去警告他們
The Jaegers,
機甲獵人
the breach,
突破點
the plan.
那個計劃
It's not going to work.
不會成功的
Disengaging transport.
脫離運輸機
Loccent,
任務控制室
all ports sealed.
封閉機身
Ready to submerge.
準備下潛
All ports sealed.
機身封閉
Ready to submerge.
準備下潛
Both neural handshakes at 100%.
兩組皆達百分之百神經握合
Neural handshake confirmed, sir.
神經握合確認，長官
Two actives still in circle formation in the Guam quadrant.
兩個怪獸仍然在關島海域盤旋
Code names: Scunner, Raiju.
代號：惡棍、雷獸
Both category 4.
兩隻都是第四量級
Roger that.
收到
Half a mile to the ocean cliff,
還有半英里就到海底峭壁
we jump!
在那裡躍下
It's 3,000 meters to the breach.
往下三千公尺就是突破點
Half a mile!
半英里
I can't even see a damn inch ahead!
這裡伸手不見五指
How are we supposed to deliver the bomb
我們要怎樣才能把炸彈送達
Visibility's zero.
能見度等於零
Switching to instruments now.
改用儀器導向
Sir!
長官
Gipsy, you have movement on your right. Three o'clock! Three o'clock!
吉普賽，你右邊三點鍾方向有動靜
100 feet radius, clear.
半徑一百英尺內，淨空
Right flank's clear. I got nothing.
右側淨空
什麼也沒看到
Left now! And movin' fast!
到左邊了，移動超快
Fastest Kaiju on record!
史上最快的怪獸
I don't see anything. It's movin' too fast!
我什麼都沒看到，他速度太快了
Eyes on the prize, Gipsy.
專心執行任務，吉普賽
600 meters from the drop.
距離投擲點六百公尺
400 meters and closing.
距離不到四百公尺了
Bogeys are stopping.
敵人停下來了
Striker!
衝鋒號
Bogeys are stopping. One o'clock.
敵人停在一點鍾方向
Marshal, what are you doing!
元帥，你在幹嘛
They're stopping.
他們停下來了
Why the hell are they stopping!
為什麼
I don't give a damn, sir!
我才不管，長官
We're 300 meters from the jump!
我們距離跳躍點只有三百公尺
Something's not right!
有事不對勁
Striker, the bogeys aren't following.
衝鋒號，敵人沒有跟上來
Take the leap now!
現在就跳下去
Don't do it!
不要跳
Don't do it, it's not gonna work!
沒用的
Move, you fascist!
閃開，你這個莽夫
Blowing up the breach, it's not gonna work!
這樣無法炸毀突破點
What do you mean What's not gonna work
什麼意思為何沒用
Sir, just because the breach is open
長官，突破點打開
does not mean you're gonna be able to get a bomb through.
不代表能把炸彈丟入
The breach genetically reads the Kaiju
突破點會掃描怪獸的基因
like a barcode at the supermarket and then lets them pass.
就像超市結賬的讀碼機，讓他們通過
Okay, so you're gonna have to fool the breach into thinking that you have the same code!
你必須騙過突破點，讓它以為你有相同條碼
And how are we supposed to do that
這要怎麼辦到
By making it think you are a Kaiju.
讓它以為你是怪獸
You have to lock onto the Kaiju, ride it into the breach.
抓緊怪獸，騎他通過突破點
The throat will then read the Kaiju's genetic code and let you pass.
頸部會掃描怪獸的基因密碼，帶你通過
If you don't do it, the bomb will deflect off the breach
如果不這麼做，炸彈會像以前那樣在突破點彈回
like it always has and the mission will fail.
然後任務會失敗
All right, now that you've heard all that,
夠了，現在廢話聽完了
Striker, take the leap!
衝鋒號，快跳吧
Sir!
長官
I have a third signature emerging from the breach!
突破點傳來第三隻怪獸讀數
Third signature emerging from the breach.
It's a triple event.
是三起事件
Oh, God, I was right.
老天，我是對的
How big is it
有多大
What category
什麼量級
Category 5.
第五量級
Striker,
衝鋒號
it's a category 5.
是第五量級
The first ever.
史上首見
Striker, we see him.
衝鋒號，我們看到了
We're right behind you, about 100 meters.
我們在你後方一百公尺處
We're gonna come around your three o'clock, try to flank him.
我們會繞到你三點鍾方向，從側面攔截他
Standard two-team formation.
採用標準的兩組陣式
Just keep him busy for a few mi...
先拖延他一下…
brace for impact!
準備撞擊
Chain sword deployed.
釋出屠獸劍
Let's get this son of a bitch!
我們殺了這混帳東西
Gipsy, comin' up on your 12 o'clock!
吉普賽，從你十二點鍾方向
Full speed!
全速來襲
Get out of the way!
快閃開
The release is jammed!
開關卡住了
We can't deliver the payload, sir!
我們無法投擲炸彈，長官
We're still armed.
炸彈已啟動
But the hull is compromised!
但機艙嚴重受損
Half our systems are offline, sir.
有一半系統無法連線，長官
We need to override the...
我們需要越過…
Both Kaijus converging on Striker fast!
兩隻怪獸快速夾擊衝鋒號
Hang on, Striker! We're comin' to ya!
撐住，衝鋒號我們來了
No! Gipsy!
不吉普賽
Do not come to our aid!
不要過來
Do you copy
聽到嗎
Hang on!
撐住
Stay as far back as you can!
離我們越遠越好
We can still reach you. We're comin' for you.
還來得及，我們來幫你
No, Raleigh, listen to me.
不，萊利，聽我說
You know exactly what you have to do!
你知道你得做什麼
Gipsy is nuclear!
吉普賽有核能引擎
Take her to the breach!
帶她去突破點
I hear you, sir.
知道了，長官
Headin' for the breach.
前往突破點
Structural damage,
結構損毀
Now....
現在...
80%.
百分之八十
Mako.
真子
Listen.
聽我說
You can finish this.
你能完成這任務
I'll always be here for you.
我會永遠在你身邊
You can always find me in the drift.
你能在浮動聯結中找到我
We're a walking nuclear reactor.
我們是移動的核子反應爐
We can destroy the breach.
我們能摧毀突破點
What can we do, sir
我們能做什麼，長官
We can clear a path!
我們能開路
For the lady!
為女士開路
They're gonna detonate the payload.
他們要引爆炸彈
Well, my father always said:
我父親總是說：
He said if you have the shot, you take it!
若能命中目標，那就開槍吧
So let's do this!
我們上吧
It was a pleasure, sir.
很榮幸與您共事，長官
Sensei.
老師
Aishitemasu.
我會想念你的
All systems critical.
所有系統狀況危急
Fluid loss.
流體損耗
Systems are critical!
系統狀況危急
Fuel is leaking!
燃料外洩
Our right leg's crippled!
我們的右腿也瘸了
Code red.
紅色警戒
Let's finish this.
我們來完成任務
All systems critical.
所有系統危急
What are they doing
他們在幹什麼
Finishing the mission.
完成任務
Loccent. We have the Kaiju carcass.
任務控制室，怪獸屍體到手
We're heading for the breach.
我們正前往突破點
You guys better be right.
希望你們是對的
Cause one way or another,
因為無論如何
we're gettin' this thing done.
我們都要完成這任務
On my count, rear jets!
聽我口令，啟動後翼噴射系統
Three,
三
two,
二
one.
一
Now!
開動
Hold on.
抓好了
Mako's oxygen is down. Half capacity!
真子的氧氣供應量降到一半
Can you reroute it
能重新連線嗎
I'm tryin', sir.
我正在努力，長官
Hold on, Mako.
抓好，真子
I'm gonna burn this son of a bitch.
我要燒死這個渾蛋
They're in.
他們進去了
They're in!
It worked.
成功了
Oxygen main, left hemisphere, critical levels.
左大腦半球，氧氣供應危急，供氧降低
Operating at 15% capacity.
至百分之十五
10% capacity.
百分之十
5% capacity.
百分之五
He's givin' her his oxygen.
他把自己的氧氣給她
Right hemisphere oxygen...
右半球氧氣...
It's okay now, Mako.
沒事了，真子
critical level.
供應危急
We did it.
我們辦到了
I can finish this alone.
剩下的我可以自己完成
All I have to do is fall.
我只需要跌落
Anyone can fall.
任何人都可以跌落
Raleigh, your oxygen levels are critical now.
萊利，你的氧氣含量很危急
You don't have much time.
時間不多了
Start the core meltdown and get out of there.
開始核心熔毀程序，然後快逃
Do you hear me
聽到了嗎
Get out of there now!
現在就離開
One pod is ejected.
一個逃生艙彈出
No detonation, sir.
沒有引爆，長官
Loccent, if you can still hear me,
控制室，如果聽得到的話
I'm initiating reactor override now.
我要開始熔毀反應爐了
(故障)
Manual activation required.
請用手動啟動
What's goin' on!
怎麼回事
Trigger's offline! He has to do it by hand.
系統斷線，他得用手動
He's out of time.
沒時間了
He has to self-destruct now.
得現在就引爆
Manual activation required.
請用手動啟動
No!
不
Manual override initiated.
手動引爆開始
Core meltdown in t-minus 60.
六十秒後開始核心熔毀
Reactor meltdown in 55 seconds.
五十五秒後反應爐熔毀
50 seconds.
五十秒
(渦輪廢氣沖放)
Evac pod engaged.
逃生艙啟動
Five...
五...
Four...
四...
Three...
三...
Two...
二...
One.
一
Reactor meltdown commence.
反應爐熔毀
Direct hit!
直接命中
The breach has collapsed!
突破點關閉了
To the choppers!
出動直升機
To the choppers now!
立刻出動直升機
Visuals on first pod.
目擊第一個逃生艙
Tracking solid.
訊號清晰
Vital signs are good.
生命徵象良好
Okay, where's the second pod
很好，第二個在哪
I'm tracking it, but I'm getting no vital signs.
我在追蹤，但沒有生命跡象
I can't find his pulse.
我找不到他的脈搏
I don't think he's breathing.
他的呼吸停止了
Can you read his pulse
讀得到脈搏嗎
Raleigh
萊利
Does he have a pulse
他有脈搏嗎
I don't know.
我不知道
Mako, listen to me.
真子，聽我說
It could be the sensors are not working.
可能感應器壞了
We can't be sure.
我們無法確認
No.
不
Don't go.
不要離開我
Mako.
真子
Don't go.
不要走
Mako.
真子
Don't go. Please.
不要離開我，求求你
You're squeezing me too tight.
你把我勒得好緊
I couldn't breathe.
我不能呼吸了
This is Marshal Hercules Hansen.
我是赫丘裡斯韓森元帥
The breach is sealed.
突破點被封閉了
Stop the clock!
停止倒數
Mako, Raleigh.
真子、萊利
We have your position.
我們知道你們位置
The choppers are on their way.
J-just hang on.
請稍候
Are you okay
你們還好嗎
Do you copy
收到了嗎
guys
兩位
導演：吉勒摩戴托羅
電影劇本：特拉維斯·比徹姆 & 吉勒摩戴托羅
故事：崔維斯畢奇漢
制片：湯瑪斯突爾 & 強賈西尼
制片：吉勒摩戴托羅 & 瑪莉派倫特
主演：查理漢納
配樂：拉敏賈瓦帝
主演：伊卓瑞斯艾巴
主演：菊池凜子
主演：查理戴
主演：朗帕爾曼
Where is my goddamn shoe
我的鞋子死哪去了
When the earth collides
two hearts, two souls remain
one love of humankind
in heaven's name
no time for fear or blame
inside, we are the same
we feel it all
we feel the rise before the fall
there's no dividing us
we feel it all
we feel it
the rise and fall
we drift inside each other
all we have is one another
united, we can never fall
we feel it all
we feel the rise before the fall
there's no dividing us
we feel it all, we feel it all
we feel it all
we feel the rise before the fall
there's no dividing us
we feel it all, we feel it all
great scientist minds
militaries combine to form the greatest weapons
to defend mankind
from the bottomless pit is the apocalypse
Egypt, okinawa, they threaten the populous
nations of man must stand this terror
two hearts ripped apart, they come together
some bonds we enjoin, they cannot be severed
whether creed or color, we all need each other
and look beyond these borders to see each other
the fate of the world is upon our shoulders
a soldier tells his father goodbye
you see the crowd mist
a gleam of hope appears in his eye
no one knows for whom the bell tolls
a strong mighty body, 100 tons of steel
kaiju
facing the enemy that stands before us
we feel it all
they trying to destroy us
we feel the rise before the fall
there's no dividing us
we feel it all, we feel it all
we feel it all
we feel the rise before the fall
there's no dividing us
we feel it all, we feel it all
we drift inside each other
all we have is one another
united, we can never fall
（謹以此片獻給怪獸大師）
（雷哈利豪森以及本多豬四郎）